SUBS BY: ERIK VERHAGEN and 防水的鱼
ORIGINALS FROM: NiCkkkDoN
北朝鲜
"North Korea"
求求你们了，求求你们，我不是你们想要的人
Please, please I'm not who you think I am.
我真的不是……
I am really not who you think I am.
求你们了，我不是间谍。
Please I am not a spy
让我回家吧。
Please let me go home.
再给你次机会
Try again
我不是间谍，我只是个做生意的
I am not a spy, I'm a businesswoman.
我在一家油气企业工作,如果你们不信，可以打电话给他们
I work in the sale of petroleum and gas.
你是到这来破坏我们的原子能计划的。
You are here to sabotage our nuclear ambition.
我不是间谍。 我不是间谍
I'm not a spy. I'm not a spy.
我不是间谍
I'm not a spy.
低下头，直到我们完成交易什么也别说
Keep your head down and do not say anything till we make the the swap.
以防万一金正日他改变主意
In case Kim Jong-Il here changes his mind.
交换
Exchange.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你不明白什么？
Don't understand what?
所有的条款都表明你们应该放弃我，
为了一条命不值得暴露身份
All the rules say to leave me, that one life is not worth blowing operational cover.
你说的对
You got that right.
如果为了全局着想我们可以牺牲个人
If we have to lose someone for the greater good.
我们会的
We will.
那你为甚麽还有这么做？
So why did you do it?
这个……
Well...
我什么也没做
I didn't do it.
他做的
He did.
从发现你的下落开始，就没有什么能阻挡他了
Once he found out where you were, there was no stopping him.
他去求参议院……
He petitioned the Senate...
国务院……
State department...
我们可不想为了这个出名，所以我想在他闹出乱子之前还是我们先来解决它吧。
We didn't need the publicity, so I figured we better do something or he was gonna do it himself
华盛顿
"Washington"
你好
Hi
早上好，结婚纪念日快乐
Good Morning - Happy Anniversary -
你想让我给你做顿早餐么？
You want me to make you breakfast?
馅饼怎么样？
How about pancakes?
你要下厨？
You're cooking?
你开什么玩笑，你喜欢我做的饭
You're joking, you like my cooking.
德国人不开玩笑
Germans don't joke.
波特喜欢我做的菜
Bert likes my cooking.
把你的虫子从桌上拿下去
Get your bugs off the table.
它们是蜘蛛（蜘蛛属于节肢动物，不属于昆虫，昆虫只有六条腿）
它们就是虫子
They're spiders. - They're bugs. -
蜘蛛。 虫子
Spiders. - Bugs. -
你在办公时间干这个？
Are you doing this on company time?
今天是我的结婚纪念日，我想要一切都完美
It's my anniversary and I want it to be perfect.
但是，
But,
这个看起来一点都不性感
That is not sexy.
不，这叫功利主义，功利主义在现在就是性感
No, but it is utilitarian and utilitarian is the new sexy.
找到线索了，姓奥特撒，名奥特木
Ran the trace, first name Usem, last name Utsa
发现有用的情报了么？ 只有一条
Any verifiable hits? - Only one -
弗朗西斯，帮我个忙
Francis, do me a favour...
把这个锁进保险箱直到明天
stick it in the safe till tomorrow
今天matahari要大干一夜了，——是长官，这就来——
Matahari here's got a big night tonight - Yes sir, Right away Sir -
长官？
Sir?
我对你来说是个长官么？
Do I look like a Sir to you?
从头到脚
From head to toe.
我正奇怪他为什么没叫你殿下？
I was surprised because he didn't call you His Majesty.
我只喜欢他们的戒指，
I like the ring of that.
我认为我更喜欢你我的殿下。（此处为调情）
I think I prefer Your Majesty.
我有那么年轻么？（意为“你不是喜欢小姑娘么”）
Was I ever that young?
风华正茂
Younger
椭圆工作室的简报做的怎么样了？
How did the Oval Office briefing go?
你知道，还那样
You know, the usual
总统总是想在今天就知道俄国明天要发生什么
The President wants to know what happens in Russia the day before it happens.
你怎么样？我听说采访进行的不错。
What about you? I heard that interview went well.
嗯……说谎呗
Hm... Fingers crossed
你确定么？
Are you sure about this?
一旦见报，就覆水难收了。
Once you start pushing paper, there is no way back.
我上次出国的时候有一种强烈的感情困惑着我
I had the strangest feeling when I was out last time.
我想家了
I was homesick.
想家？
Homesick?
长官
Sir
我们找到了个线人……
We got a walk-in...
一个叛国者，就在十分钟前，
a defector, 10 minutes ago.
在这？——我想他不会是要买个假身份吧。——
Here? - Guess he's not buying our cover. -
他不是骗子么？ ——他是个俄国人——
He's bonafide? - He's Russian. -
说他自己是个FSB，其他的就问不出来了
Says he's FSB, won't give us any more.
没人见过他，——他的英语怎么样？
He's a strange guy. - How's his English?
过得去，但不是很好
Passable, not great.
我们需要你去说服他——泰德，麦克在家等我呢
We need you to convince him of the settlement - Ted, Mike's gonna be waiting for me at home) -
是呀，我也有一班飞机要赶
Yes, and I got a plane to catch.
来吧邵特，在解决棘手问题上没人比你更快。
Come on Salt, no one can sort out a nut job faster that you.
我只有25分钟，——我有26分钟，我们走——
I got 25 minutes. - I got 26. Let's go. -
——防水的鱼——
你好泰德，我们要来搅局了，
Hi Ted, we're crashing the party.
豆子身（这算什么姓氏？）——邵特（盐）
Peabody. - Salt. -
请把头套摘掉
Please remove the hood.
麦克风开启
Microphones are on.
检验步调
Checking levels.
基础录音
Baseline recording.
神经扫描开启
Neuroscan is up.
准备好了
Ready to go.
面谈开始于14：42分
Interview has commenced at 14:42.
你结婚了。
You're married.
对一个训练有素的特工人员来说丈夫是很分心的
A husband must be a distraction for a female intelligence officer.
我们到这来是为了谈你的
We are here to talk about you
那么你就什么名字？
So what is your name?
我的名字是 埃里克*瓦西里*奥洛夫
My name is Alec Vassilly Orlov
我患有癌症
I have cancer
我都快哭了
I'm moved.
你到这来卖情报是为了买化疗药品还是你太怕死了
Are you selling secrets for chemo or are you afraid of dying?
如果我通过诅咒自己的方式而想得到一些东西，
那就说明我已经没什么可怕的啦。
If I have gained anything by daming myself, it is that I no longer have anything to fear.
俄国也在死去——埃里克*瓦西里*奥洛夫——
Russia is also dying - Alec Vasili Orlov. -
他1993年在西伯利亚出现过
Shows up in 1993 in Novosibirsk, Siberia
他入境时的身份是作为FSB
He checks out as FSB.
监控表明他这的得了癌症
The test says he's truthful on the cancer.
看看1993年之前……
Prior to 1993...
什么也没有
Nothing...
1993年之前他不存在
He doesn't exist.
我还有个约会要赶，奥洛夫先生
I have somewhere I need to be, Mr. Orlov
所以如果你不介意的话，可以不再说废话了么？
So if you wouldn't mind getting to the point.
在1975年
冷战期间
Cold war
在体育馆里，一个叫Sacha Jordorovich的苏维埃奥林匹克摔跤手
In a gymnasium, a Sovjet Olympic wrestler named Sacha Jordorovich,
和那个年代唯一一个女性国际象棋大师级棋手
Meets for the first time,
见了第一面
the only female Chess Grandmaster of her era.
一个月以后他们纠结婚了
Within a month they were married.
一年之内他们有个一个孩子
And within a year, a child.
又过了一个月
One month more,
那个孩子又被送回了医院
The child was back in the same hospital.
在哪里有什么在秘密的进行
And it's something got a secret
只过了几天，那个孩子，突然就死了
And within days after that, the child, suddenly was dead.
是的
Yes,
一个孩子就这么死了
A child was dead,
而且
And yes,
那孩子被埋葬了
The child was buried.
但那个栔考夫婴儿并没有死
But the Chenkov baby was still alive.
而成了另一个男人的财产
And became the property of another man.
他是头号间谍，他制定了一个俄国爱国者能制定的最伟大的计划
A masterspy who had devised the greatest plan a Russian patriot could ever invent;
一个能毁灭美国的计划
A plan to destroy America.
这一切都始于一个叫李*哈维*奥斯瓦尔德的美国人
It had all started with an American named Lee Harvey Oswald.
在1959年
In 1959
他移居俄国
He emmigrated to Russia.
三年后
Three years later
他回到了家乡，但这个回到美国的男人其实是个俄国间谍
Returned to his home. But the man who came home to America, was in fact a Russian spy.
他叫埃里克
Named Alec.
1963年十一月22日
On November 22, 1963
埃里克完成了三个新计划的第一个
Alec has became the first success of thee new program.
而成为了苏维埃的英雄
And a hero in the Soviet Union.
于是间谍主管得到而来一个机会，去创造更多像埃里克那样的人。
The spy master was now given the go ahead, to create many more like Alec.
秘密特工组织
Scores of agents.
有男有女
Males and females
把他们安置在美国
To be substituted for Americans.
在一个废弃的学校里，他们在学习俄语之前就学习英语
In an abandoned monestery they were learning English before they were learning Russian.
了解美国的风俗习惯
Drilled in idiom, idiosynchrocy
在接受的严格的精神和体能训练之后
And by methods of rigorous physical and physological training.
间谍主管创造出了钢铁战士
The spy master made warriors of iron.
不可置疑，不可动摇
Unquestioned and unbreakable.
这故事就要弄死我了，老兄
You're killing me, man.
什么时候能讲到仙女出现？
When does the good fairy come in?
永远没有
No, never...
这是个绝望的故事
It's a story without hope.
楔考夫的情况符合一个美国家庭的女孩
Chankov had matched a girl to an American family
发生而来事故，父母都死了
There was an accident, the family died.
所以偰考夫被送往美国
So Chankov was sent to America.
过着一种完全被谎言覆盖的生活……
To live a complete lie...
而且知道现在都一直在等待有一天能开始从内部攻击，dayx
And to patiently await the day to attack from within, day X.
那个长期任务就在这，
The long awaited mission is here.
偰考夫会到达你的城市，杀掉俄国总统
Chankov will travel to your city to kill the President of Russia.
就在前总统的葬礼上，他就会行动
At the funeral of U.S. Vice President, CHankov) will be (so er)
行动？
So er)? )
那是个乡野传说
It's an urban legend.
潜伏的俄国特工潜入美国本土进行暗杀和破坏活动
Russian sleeper agents inserted into American society to carry out sabotage and assassinations
没有可能他们一等数年就为了那终极一击
Most likely they are waiting years to do a knock-
很有可能……
Seemingly
什么？ 你不相信有刺客这一说？
What? You don't believe in moles?
我相信高手刺客，但我不相信有超人
I believe in moles, just not the boogey man.
尤其是他们的任务还是刺杀自己的总统
Specially if the plan is to kill their own president.
这个家伙在放烟雾弹
This guy's selling smoke.
手工，伊娃
Wrap it up, Eve.
所以说这有一个俄国特工要去杀俄国总统
So a Russian agent is gonna kill the Russain president. Right?
好吧
OK
非常感谢
Thank you very much
那么你想用这条信息交换什么呢？
And what would you like in return for this information?
我只是单纯的希望能帮助你去做你想干的事。
I simply wish to help you do what you need to do.
你真是太好了
You're good
KA_ 计划真是陀完美无缺的狗屎
KA-program is brilliant bull-shit.
但我还有工作要做
But I'm officially off-duty.
所以你把你剩下的故事跟我的同事讲完吧。
So tell the rest of your little story to my colleagues.
邵特——什么事？——
Salt. - Yes. -
那个俄国特工的名字就是邵特
The name of the Russian agent is Salt.
我的名字是爱福林*邵特
My name is Evelyn Salt.
那么就是那个俄国特工
Then you are a Russian spy.
他说的是真话
"Truthfull"
到现在为止，这个人说的每一句话都是真的
So far, the FMRI is truthfull on everything he said.
泰德
Ted.
通知安全局让他们一定找到我丈夫
Call Protective Services and make sure they find my husband.
你要干什么？——我的打个电话——
What are you doing? - I need to get to the phone -
不，不，尤其在听了那些话之后
No, no, not after the neuro-scan.
我都能在六次里骗过那机器五次，我接受过训练，那个人也是
I can beat that thing five times out of six. I'm trained and so is he.
我要给我丈夫大个电话
I need my phone and I need to call my husband.
让我给我丈夫打电话——好吧，让我看着——
Let me contact with my husband - Let me see it. -
他提到我的结婚戒指是有原因的，泰德
There is a reason he mentioned my wedding ring Ted.
但他们暴露一个间谍，他们就会全都暴露你知道的。
When they blow up a spy, they blow up their whole covered life and you know that.
你还记得亨利的妻子么？
Remember the what happened to Henry's wife?
是，我记得
Yes, I do.
“请在响声之后留言”“再见”
"Please leave a message after the beep" "Bye"
“亲爱的，是我，如果你听到这个了就打给我好么？”
Honey, it's me. Please call me as soon as you get this.
好了亲爱的，你会尽快听到回音的
Okay sweetheart, as soon as you get this.
非常快
Godspeed.
找个人来问问这个烂人
Someone interrogate this piece of shit.
找个喜欢得到答案的
Someone who enjoys getting answers.
你看，伊娃，你得冷静下来……
Look Eve, try to stay calm...
我不是个该死的俄国间谍
I am not a goddamn Russia spy.
谁也没说你是
I didn't say you were.
让我们到我的办公室解决这件事
Let's go up to my office so we can sort this out.
不不，不行，我们得到一个安全的地方去
No, no, we gotta go to a secure location.
就现在
Now
好吧
OK
没有比这里更安全的地方了
There is no safer place than this
伊娃
Eve,
五分钟
Five minutes.
给保安部打电话让他们找麦克
Call Protective Services and tell them to find Mike.
就一会
Give us a sec.
我知道我在这里给你找了麻烦，不过我就要五分钟
I know that we're heading into your juristiction here but I'm asking you for 5 minutes.
不行
No.
就算我答应了，你也没有五分钟给她，我得和她谈
If I have to yes, you can't have five minutes with her. I have to talk with her
她现在很不安——我不管——
She's scared? - I don't care -
这里一个刺客在俄国领事馆，泰德
There's a mole in Russia house Ted.
一定有，我能肯定
There's a mole in Russia house and I am sure
请进电梯
Please step in the elevator.
又出什么事了
What the hell is that?
长官
Sir
我的上帝
Jesus Chirst.
又是他，到目前为止没有在街上发现他
There he is again. - No sign of him so far on the street. -
他是在我们关闭这里之前两分钟逃离的
Two minutes to go before we lock down.
我们刚找到的这个，先生
We just got a match, Sir.
1981年，请看这里
In 1981, and here this is
就是他，——过去也有过好日子——
That's him. - Used to be a heavyweight once upon a time. -
把这个图像发到飞机场，火车站出租车行，覆盖九个街区。
Get that picture out everywhere tickets for the airport, train station and taxi station, the whole nine yards.
给我直接接内线 MEDFORD_是 先生——
Get me director Medford on a secure line. - Yes, Sir -
上面的屏幕，这是即时的么？
Top-right screen, is that live?
是的
Yes sir.
她要去哪？ 跟踪她
Where is she going? Track her.
安检
Rink Petroleum Security.
在你左边有个女人
You have a woman to your left behind you.
爱福林*邵特
Evelyn Salt.
看不见她了，——该死——
We lost visual of her. - Damn -
她去哪了？
Where'd she go?
嗨 爱德华，麦克在么？
Hey Edward, is Mike there?
不，对不起他去吃午餐了
No, sorry he went to lunch.
二楼，楼梯间
Stairwell, second floor.
那层有什么？
What's on that floor?
空的
It's empty.
监控摄像——隔离叫上海豹突击队——
Surveillance cameras - Isolate and seal. -
关闭电梯电源
Kill the power to the elevatordoors.
我们抓到他了
We got her.
OK.
找个突击队来见我在南面的楼梯间
Get a tactical team to meet me on the south stairwell.
是，长官
Yes sir.
Director Medford sir.
我一会儿打给她
I'll call her back.
该死——又看不见了——
Shit. - I lost visual. -
她去哪了？ 快告诉我
Where is she Albert. Talk to me.
快点
Come on
这，在审讯室。调上来
There, interrogation room. Bring it up.
你找到他了么——你在干什么？伊娃？——
Have you found him? - What the hell are you doing Eve? -
有个突击队30秒后就要找到你了。快把你那该死的内裤从摄像头上拿下来
There's a tac team coming at you in 30 seconds. Get your goddamn panties off the camera so we can see you.
你找的我丈夫了么？
Have you found my husband?
这些小子们可不是闹着玩的
These boys don't fool around Eve.
求你了，你不和我说话让我真么帮你？——找到麦克在打给我——
Please, I can't help you unless you talk to me. - Call me when you find Mike. -
好了，把门打开两英尺，我们就放催泪弹
Ok, open the doors two feet. We're gonna gas her.
真的有个这必要么
Is this necessary?
你想让我开枪打他么？
Want me to kill her?
叫一个医疗队就位
Put a medical team in place now.
好，听我指挥
Ok, on my count.
进入
Enter
天啊1
Jesus Christ.
她哪去了？
Where is she?
找到她
Find her.
放大
Bring it up.
他正在穿过街区
She's crossing the street.
打开那该死的摄像机
Pan the goddamned camera
追踪到定位
Back that up and zoom in.
停
Stop.
你到底要干吗？
What the hell are you doing Eve?
麦克一个小时前离开而了办公室
Michael Krauss left his office an hour ago.
邵特的家离这里20分钟路程
Salt's apartment is 20 minutes from here.
我们可以包围那个地方，但他不会回去的
We can cover it, but she won't go there.
如果他真的关心她丈夫他就会去的
She will if she's serious about Mike.
呆在屋里好么？
This stays inhouse ok?
Taxi.
海赫斯大街，我会告诉你在哪停
Hughesstreet. I'll tell you where to stop.
你好，我是麦克，请在听到响声后留言
Hello, this is Mike. Please leave a message after the beep
他是世界著名的节肢动物学家，伊娃
He is one of the world's top arachnologists, Eve.
所以他可以自由出入北朝鲜的边界
And as such enjoys almost unrestricted access to the border of North Korea.
所以
So,
带上你的虫子，去认识他
Brush up on your bugs and get to know him.
他是让我们潜入的完美伪装
He's the perfect cover to get us inside.
麦克
Mike,
宝贝
Honey,
你好宝贝，到这来
Hey baby, Come here.
很好。爸爸呢？
It's allright. Where is daddy?
爸爸在哪？
Where's daddy?
行动，行动
Go, go.
浴室没有人
Bathroom, clear.
厨房没有人
Kitchen, clear.
书房没有人
Office, clear.
起居室，安全
Living room, clear.
60秒后全体到外面去
Everybody out in 60 seconds.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
她不在这，她丈夫也不见踪影
She's not here and no sign of the husband either.
你就从没想过那个俄国人可能在撒谎么
Did it ever occur to you that maybe that Russian was lying?
那她为什么跑
Why'd she run?
我不知道，因为那要把她关起来
I don't know, cause you were gonna lock her up? -
从她的角度看看，也许他的丈夫真的身处险境
See it from her perpective. Maybe her husband is some real danger.
也许，看在上帝的份上，邵特是清白的
Maybe, God forbid, Salt is who she says she is.
也许对你来说是，但我的任务就是抓到她 然后问清楚
Maybe is your department. Mine is catching her so we can find out.
条款里说的很清楚，抓住她，搞定她
Protocol is clear: we bring her in, we bring her down.
你对这个女人的身份有什么见解么
Do you have any idea who this woman is?
那些她为这个国家所做的一切，这些对你来说就没有一点意义？
What she's done for this country. Does that mean anything to you?
有么？
Should it?
能帮我个忙么？——好啊——
Can you do me a favor? - Yes -
帮我照顾它。——好——
Can you Bert-sit for me? - Yes -
这有一些钱
Here's are some money.
你在做家庭作业
Did you do your homework?
对，数学
Yes, Mathematics
我恨数学
I hate math
嗨
Hi.
再次见到你很高兴
It's nice to see you again
你在跟我说话？——是，我在这里见过你——
Are you talking to me? - Yes, I've seen you here before. -
是，我常来这
Yes, I come here often.
你呢？
And you?
不，我在这里的博物馆工作
No, I am working here at the museum.
我是个节肢动物学家
I am an arachnologist.
一个什么
A what?
我抓住蜘蛛了
I hunt spiders.
抓住她
Got her.
她正向北面跑向地铁站
She's heading north toward the metro-station.
她在东边
She's east-bound.
她在那
There she is.
所有小组向南去桥上
All teams southbound toward the bridge.
所有小组已进入
All units are in.
站住
Stop!
把枪都收起来
Take it back, hold your fire.
站住
Stop!
邵特
SALT!
别开枪，我是无辜的——
Don't shoot, I'm innocent -
趴在地上
On the ground now
别开枪
Just don't shoot.
邵特，趴在地上
Salt, on the ground.
我的找到我丈夫——你为什么跑——
I have to find my husband - why'd you run? -
去找我丈夫——为什么——
To find my husband - For what reason? -
别开枪
Don't shoot.
别动
Stay back.
我是无辜的，有人陷害我
I'm innocent, somebody set me up.
别逼我放倒你，邵特——把枪放下——
(Don't make me put you down Salt. - put the gun down. -
快点投降——不——
Give yourself up. - No. -
趴在地上
On the ground.
我们会解决它的，我发誓
We'll sort this out, I promise.
我们的把你交给上头处理
We gotta bring you in Salt.
有人要杀掉俄国总统你知道的
Someone is gonna kill the Russian president you know that.
我们的做的什么
Do something about it.
投降吧，——你最该担心的是这个——
Give yourself up. - That's what you should be worried about. -
没有地方可逃了
There's nowhere to run.
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything.
她在一个蓝色的集装箱上，向北驶去
She's on a blue semi, heading north.
现在就封锁道路，
Get a roadblock in place now.
她在那，在一个油罐车上
There she is. On the tanker.
停下
Stop!
不！
No!
你是我的朋友，你却弄了个刺客在你的队里，——我们现在还不知道是不是——
You my friend, have got a mole in your group - We don't know that yet. -
事实就是，他是个该死的受过训练的骗子，找了个丈夫做掩护
In fact, she's a trained goddamned liar set up with a husband to protect our cover.
你为什么就是不告诉我你对这件事的真实想法
Why don't you tell me how you really feel about it.
开枪打她的肩膀
Hit her on the shoulder!!
好吧，下去
Ok, take it down.
该死
Shit.
OK
泰德，我知道你是她朋友
Ted, I know you're her friend.
但我们得在纽约布下天罗地网。
But we gotta drop a net on New York.
我们现在就得这么干
We gotta do it now.
我会上报保密局这件事的细节
I'll the Secret Service on the details.
告诉他们邵特可能会有所行动
Tell 'em Salt might be coming their way.
她在那
Here she is.
你看到这个了么
You see this?
在她还是个孩子的时候，她在俄国呆过
Salt spent time in Russia when she was a child.
1988年她父母车祸丧生时她就在他们身边
She was with her parents in 1988 in a car accident when they died,
他们是驻俄大使馆工作人员孩子们的老师，
They were teachers at the American Embassy for the children of the staff there.
这就是为什么我们把她带到俄国
That's why we put her on Russia in the first place.
我们得向纽约上交一份计划，就在今晚
We need to get on a plan to New York. Tonight.
俄国总统今晨到达曼哈顿
Russian President arrived in Manhattan this morning.
伊芙琳
Evelyn.
看着我
Look at me.
如果不是在这，我会杀了他们
If it were not there another way of killing them
你不该来这的，——我不明白——
You shouldn't have come here - I don't understand. -
现在他们知道你是谁了
Now they know who you are.
谁知道了？
Who?
伊芙琳
Evelyn.
谁？
Who?
我会接受你的一切
I would accept anything about you,
我必须知道
But I need to know.
看着我
Look at me.
告诉我吧，好么
Just tell me, ok?
告诉我
Just tell me.
我在……
I work...
我在中央情报局工作
I work for the CIA.
你明白了么？
You see?
我们是不会有结果的
There is no future for us.
你和我在一起永远不会安全
And you're not safe with me.
那我就不要安全
I don't want to be safe.
我了解你
I know you.
所以我想和你在一起
And I want to be with you.
我想和你共度余生
I want to spend the rest of my life with you.
好的
OK
欢迎来到纽约Hernandez夫人，就住一晚？
Welcome to New York Ms. Hernandez. One night?
是的
Yes.
hernadez夫人,你要我们帮你拎行李么？——不，我自己能行——
Ms. Hernandez, do you want any help with your luggage? - No, that's fine thanks. -
周一在纽约
On Monday here in New York City
前总统的葬礼
The funeral of Vice-President Maxwell
前五届美国总统以及一位伟大的战士
Former 5-termsenator of the United States of America and a great warrior
为美国开创了与俄国外交的新篇章
Probably extend his legacy to a new era of Russia's relationship
俄国总统自莫斯科前往这里来吊唁一位
Russian President Matveyev has joined from Moscow to be an
他称之为西方好友的伟人
honorary forbarer of the man who called he good friend in the West
警戒情况怎么样
What's the security perimeter?
我们太靠近了，所以我们封锁了整个街区
We're too deep inside so we have secured the entire block.
这些都是特工
And those are secret agents.
是中央情报局的，别担心
The CIA so, relax.
这个真好笑
That's real funny.
我不知道你的人还会讲笑话
Didn't know you guys told jokes.
让开让开
Away, away
总统先生
Mr. President.
在总统讲完悼词和颂歌之后
After the President finishes the chorus and the eulogy...
如果在这样的戒备下，她还要只身犯险，我倒是挺惊讶的
If she's gonna try anything here, it'll have to be pretty amazing.
我知道他一定会为这项工作带来更多而不只是他多年的经验
I knew he would bring more to the job than just his years of experience
我亲眼目睹了他让世界看到了美国最好的一面
I see the world what it means to be American
而今天世界回应他，“再见”
Today, the world says "Goodbye"
我去后面
I'll take the back.
我下去了，下面好像有麻烦
I'm heading down, some kind of trouble down there.
发生什么了？
What's going on?
他将永远留在我们心中，为此，他将永远为我们所敬仰
"Maybe going to have him inside of us" "for that, he will always have my respect and admiration"
放下枪
Drop it.
开枪者在十二点钟方向
Shooters at twelve o'clock.
击倒她
Take her down.
查看是否有其他武器
Check for other weapons
我们现在继续一个医疗小组
We need a medical crew in the crypt immediately.
我摸不到脉搏
I can't find a pulse.
为什么
Why?
你知道你这么做会有对少人死去么
ou have any idea how much blood is on your hands?
退后
Back off.
总统已经死了，去医院只是个程序
The president was declared dead en route to the hospital.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
是的
Yes.
看来你对他的看法是对的
You were right about her.
她本可以杀了我的
She had the drop on me Ted.
为什么她没有开枪
Why didn't she shoot?
有警察坠车了
Cops down, cops down.
把双手放在头上从车里出来
Get out of the car with your hands on your head
马上！
Get out immediately.
你叫什么名字？——我的名字叫伊芙琳*邵特
What is your name? - My name is Evelyn Salt -
你要去那所大学？普林斯顿
What college will you attend. Princeton Univercity? -
你要去哪里工作？ 中情局
Where will you work? - Central Intelligence Agency -
你能信任谁？
Who will you trust?
没有人
No one.
一定要有耐心
Be very patient.
记住你是如何被训练的
Remember your training
记住，你不是一个人
Remember, you're not the only one.
这里还有你的同伴
There are many others...
等待进攻的时机
Waiting to strike.
我们会一起进攻
And we will strike together.
等等
Wait
我一天我会和你的会和
One day I'll come for all of you.
你好伊芙琳
Hello Evelyn...
我是美国领事馆的马丁*科文索
My name is Martn Crenshaw from the U.S. Embassy.
我们对你双亲的去世非常遗憾
We're very sorry about your family's accident.
俄国的新总统已就CIA工作人员伊芙琳*邵特袭击总统事件作出回应
Russia's new president speaks about the assassination attempt by CIA officer Evelyn Salt.
总统的尸体仍在医院，而反美情绪正在俄国愈演愈烈
The body of Russian president is still in the hospital while anti-American riots have errupted in Russia.
因牵扯道俄总统
While improving the Russian President
俄方军部正处以高度戒备
Russian armed forces have been put on high alert.
以应对这突如其来的危机
Responding to a rapid escalating crisis.
美国总统路易斯在白宫召开紧急会议
President Lewis called for an urgent White House meeting.
祝福你，我亲爱的
Greetings to you dear
欢迎
Welcome
当我在华盛顿看到您是我都要哭了
When I saw you in Washington I almost was in tears.
你不该结婚的
You weren't supposed to get married.
这样做才正常
I did it to seem normal.
当你逃脱时，就连我都禁不住相信一切皆有可能
When you escaped today, not even I could have hoped for so much.
你是我最伟大的创制
You are my greatest creation.
你把我训练的很好
You trained me well.
我的丈夫 你找的他了？
My husband? You have him?
我必须得到确认
I had to be certain.
但你现在该相信我了
But now you trust me.
坚信不疑
Completely.
那么告诉我下一步该怎么做？
So, tell me what's next.
下一步，第二部分
Next, part 2.
我们将掌握这个国家的核武器
We seize control of this country's atomic weapons.
怎么做？
How?
你不会再听到我的声音了，我将实行静默
You won't hear from me again.
我的女儿
My daughter.
.
你还记得我么？
You remember me?
你想我么
Did you miss me?
我必须想么
Do I have to?
你到这里多久了
How long have you been here?
我比你晚一年离开俄国
I left Russia one year after you.
我在白宫担任安全顾问有三年了，
I have been a NATO-liaison to the White House for three years. Colonel Edward Tomasz.
而你……
And you...
你是我的目标，你的身份证明
Are my attache. Your ID.
更重要的是，我们的新任务
More importantly, our new mission.
这个地堡。白宫地下六层
The bunker, eight stories below the White House
那里是总统必须要去的地方
That's where the President needs to be.
我们要怎么做？
How do we do it?
不用担心，他会到那里去的，那是我的任务
Do not worry, he will be there. That's my job.
确保他到那里去
To make sure he's there.
那我的任务呢？
And what is my job?
你还记得我们小的时候么？
Do you remember when we were young?
你无论什么事都要第一个完成
You had to finish first in everything.
无论什么都要做到最好
You had to be the best at everything.
虽然你知道做了第一就要被鞭打，你还是要做第一
Even though you knew you would be beaten with a cane if you weren't first.
我记得……
I remember...
今晚你又要比我先了
Tonight you will finish ahead of me again.
今晚你要杀掉美国总统
Tonight you will kill America's President.
请出示证明
ID's please.
抬起头打开车厢
Pop the hood and open the trunk.
请确认
Confirm this, A Colonel Tomasz and a Major Egypt.
安全
All clear.
请进先生
Step though please Sir,
转身
Turn around.
Thank you.
耐心最重要，我们来到这里已经两年了，其他人更久
Patience is key, I've been coming here for two years. Others have been coming here even longer.
其他人，——我不知道——
What others? - Don't know. -
你是我们中最强的
You were the best of us.
而我是最弱的
And I was the least.
所以必须由其他人来完成我们未尽的事业
There must be others to finish what we begin.
泰德，你的那个俄国秘密特工邵特
Ted, your Russion CI agent Salt...
对于她 你有什么可以告诉我们的
What can you tell us about her?
我们认为他可能是个苏维埃间谍
We think she might be a Sovjet plant.
潜伏多年为了一个什么KGB计划
Inserted several years for what the KGB
那一天就叫做“day X”
called "Day X".
那一天就是标志着美国和他的盟友将受到致命威胁的一天
A day that would mark the start of a large-scale strike against the US and her allies.
你就是总统了
That should the be President now.
你有一项艰巨的任务要完成，但你会做到的
You have a big job, but you can do it.
你还是没有告诉我你的任务是什么。——回家——
You still haven't told me what your job is. - Home. -
我就要回家了
I'm going home.
你还要么，长官？——是的——
Are you okay, sir? - Yes -
我想我看见他了
I think I saw her.
谁
Who?
邵特
Salt.
我在楼梯上看见他了
I think I saw her in the corridor.
他在那
She's here.
安全。
Clear. Move.
Go.
我们在这里能看见
We may have a visual on the second assaillant. Evelyn Salt.
这不是演习
THIS IS NOT A DRILL. EVACUATE.
THIS IS NOT A DRILL
我们需要从这里到左边都安全
I need the hallway cleared to the left, now
我们现在需要去地堡
This is Jenkins. I need the bunker up and running.
如果这是俄国政府的报复行为，那它就是战争挑衅
If this was sanctioned by the Russian Government, it is an act of war.
我们走吧，先生
Let's go, Sir,
Move move.
Move, move.
关闭
Close it.
明白
Clear.
她可能跟来么？-一旦门被关闭就没人能进来
Any chance she could follow? - No one can get through that door once it's closed. -
OK
很不幸，她和你们不太一样
Unfortunately, she isn't one of your's.
OK, go.
大家跟紧，关闭闸门
Stay close. Shut the seal.
先生，我们必须假设今天就是“day x”的开始
Sir, we must discuss the probability that today is the beginning of "Day X".
总统先生，medford 在线上
Mr. President, director Medford is up.
现在是什么情况
Marianne, what is the situation?
你该看看你的屏幕
It should be coming up on your screen.
你在这里看到的是在西伯利亚的异常散热源
What you see here is a scanning thermal regions in Siberia.
这表明俄国已经开始准备他们的导弹系统
Means that the Russians are deplowying their missiles to the field.
这个消息已经得到了地面确认
And this information is confirmed on the ground.
先生，我强烈建议我们从四级预警转到二级
Sir, I strongly recommend we go tO DEFCON 2.
这是最基本的
At least on a basis.
介于俄国已经开始了导弹防御，我们也必须做好准备了
Considering the Russians are deploying, we must look at our own nuclear attack options.
这不是警告也不是威胁
It's not on table and it's not a deterrent.
我们的外门卡住了，而且没有反应
The outer door is jammed and non-responsive.
我们也失去了外面大部分监控录像的信号
We just lost the feed with most of our security camera's.
我们什么也看不见了，而且每人能进来
We are blind down here and no one can enter this place.
指挥官，我们的监控失效了，而且这里有一个POC安全系统故障
Command, our eyes are down and we have a POC security system
从这走，现在
Get out there, now.
关闭这件屋子
Seal this room.
到下面的走廊里去，注意戒备
Down that corridor, secure it.
我是总统，要求通过安全指令
Mr. President Howard Lewis, proceed with authentication.
是，先生
Yes, Mr. President,
密码验证准备就绪
Ready to commence code sir.
密码核实完毕
Authentication is confirmed.
现在都有您决定了，总统先生
It's all yours now, Mr. President.
上帝与你同在。
God be with you.
目标现在在您的控制之下，总统先生
Targets are under your control, Mr. President,
门外的监控能用么？ ——是的——
Does the camera outside the door work? - Yes -
让我看看
Put it up.
那是谁？
Who is that?
是她
It's her.
是伊芙琳*邵特
That's Evelyne Salt.
把你的武器给我，——不行，我是这里唯一可以拿武器的保安人员——
Give me your side-arm - No, that's only for Secret Service. -
去他的安全条例，我们有个敌特在外面
Screw Protocol James. we have an enemy agent out there.-
规定就是规定，先生
Protocol is protocol Sir.
你死了，就是死了
You're dead - is dead -
我是国土安全顾问
I'm the National Security Advisor.
不再是了
Not anymore.
坐下
Sit down.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我的名字，总统先生是，尼克列*特瓦斯科
My name, Mr. President is Nicolai Tarkovsky.
除非你按我说的做，否则我将是你见到的最后一个人
And unless you do exactly what I say, I will be the last person you will ever see.
让我们看看都有哪些目标可打
Let's have a look at some attack options.
去死吧
Go to hell.
泰德
Ted,
你为什么没告诉我你是我们中的一员
Why didn't you tell me?
我试过
没成功
但如果你在俄国和我们在一起，我应该认出你
But if you're with us in Russia I would've remembered you.
我属于一个更高的阶层
比你们的最高班还要高级
确认攻击的地点
Areas has confirmed the attack
发射导弹
杀死100万人
激怒所有穆斯林，
这样美国就会成为众矢之的
让我加入你吧
好么
让我加入你
好吧
俄国总统还活着
"The Russian president is alive"
我们能看到俄国总统在他出院后来到飞机场
We can see the president and is at the airport after his release from hospital
他的医生说这真是个奇迹
This is a miracle according to his doctors.
他说总统的假死是由一种毒蜘蛛的毒液导致的
The President's temporary death was attributed to Amotaliyn, a spider venom.
至少我是对的
At least I was right.
我们害怕我们会在北朝鲜失去你
I feared we may have lost there in Korea.
你应该把那个男人收纳到我们的组织里来，而不是爱上他
You were supposed to recruit the man, not fall in love with him.
这就是为什么我让奥利弗抓了他
That's why I told Orlov to pick him up.
顺便问一句，麦克怎么样了
By the way how is Michael?
奥利弗死了
Orlov is dead.
真是好消息
That's good news.
给我省了不少麻烦
Saves me the trouble.
你看，他希望你能够活着完成这项任务
You see? He wanted you to come out of this alive.
如果你需要一个人来怨
And you need a person to take the blame.
我可以扮黑脸
I'm the bad guy.
那我就是白脸
And I am the hero.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
你马上就要出名了
You are about to become a famous.
请求确认
Requests confirmation
证明完成
Identity confirmed
请求批准发射
Permission to launch
趴在地上
Get on the floor now.
我说现在
I said now!
让我看见你的手，让我看见你的手，
Show me your hands, show me your hands!
你的姓名，先生
What is your name sir?
我是CIA 的人，保护总统的
I'm from the CIA. Help the President
总统先生，先生，你能听见我说话么
Mr. President, Mr. President, can you hear me?
我要她被隔离在一个单独的房间，如果这里还有其他俄共，我不希望他们交谈
I want her alone in a room. If there are other KA's I don't want them talking.
她受过训练，如果她不想说，我们无论如何都不能让她开口
She's trained not to talk, no matter what we do to her.
如果我们要找到那些家活，我们只能靠我们自己了
If we find these people must find them ourselves.
有些人已经在这么做了
Somebody already did.
至少是他们中的一部分，——在东边的河岸，12具尸体，包括奥利弗——
At least some of them - in the East River. 12 dead, including Orlov.
谁干的
Who did that?
不知道，法医正在那边
I don't know. Forensics are on it.
请退后
Step back sir, please.
Please step back.
她攻击了温特，长官，你最好来一下
She attacked Winter sir. You'd better come up here.
坐下
Sit down.
在飞行期间的15分钟她是你的
She's yours for 15 minutes during this flight.
你为什么杀他？
Why'd you kill him?
总得有人干这个
Because somebody had to.
什么？
What?
你真的相信人们说他们是谁就是谁？
Do you think that everyone is who they say they are?
你知道奥利弗过来卖情报事有蹊跷
ou knew that something was wrong when Orlov walked in.
我也是
So did I.
你只是不知道问题出在哪
We just didn't know what it was.
泰德*温特知道
Winter did.
温特？
Winter?
你希望我相信你是温特要发射导弹，而你救了全世界？
You expect me to believe that Winter was gonna launch the nukes and you save the world?
我现在正是希望你这么做
I would like you to believe that yes.
这可是个非常严重的指控
It's a big accusation.
哦
Wow.
他现在死了，所以也没可能为自己辩护
He's dead now so he can't defend himself.
所以我猜你现在的自己做判断了
I guess you'll have to decide for yourself.
像你这样的在这里还有几个
How many more like you are there?
向我这样的？
Like me?
没有了
none
但，像他那样的
Like him?
比你能想象的还多
More than you can imagine
你真的相信一个训练有素的特工在那么近的地方还杀不了总统么？
Do you think that a trained agent will not be able to kill the President of Russia from a reasonable distance if she wanted to?
同理，还有你
Or you, for that matter.
我本可以杀你，但我没有
I could've killed you at the funeral but I didn't.
你向我投降是因为，我让你别无选择
You surrendered to me because you knew you had no choice.
你比谁都清楚
You know better.
我有选择
I had a choice.
你比谁都清楚
You know better.
如果我相信你，我没说我相信，我只是说如果我相信你
I don't believe you.
那也只有我，没有人回信的
But if I did, no else would.
那么，也许你可以帮我想想办法
Maybe you can think of a way around that.
他们从我这里夺走了一切
They took everything from me.
我会把他们全都杀光
I'll kill them all.
胡扯！
Bullshit!
去干掉他们
Go get 'em.
SUBS BY: ERIK VERHAGEN
ORIGINALS FROM: NiCkkkDoN